# **ANDREW LONDON**



## UI/UX ENGINEER

# CONTACTS



704.287.1152



london.andrewd@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/alondon

# SKILLS

TECHNICAL	
React	
React Native	
Cypress	
CSS/Sass	
HTML	
NodeJS	
SQL	
SOFTWARE	
Sketch	
Invision	
JIRA	

## **EDUCATION**

2016

#### **Frontend Engineering Track**

The Iron Yard

Charleston, SC

2013

# Web Development 101-105

Charleston Digital Corridor

Charleston, SC

2011

## **B.S. Sociology**

College of Charleston

Charleston, SC

#### **PROFILE**

Meticulous software engineer with 5+ years experience as a frontend focused developer. Highly proficient in HTML, CSS and Javascript with a deep appreciation for clean and consistent user experiences. Looking to grow into a leadership role with the opportunity to both mentor and learn from other developers.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR UI/UX ENGINEER

07.2020 - Present | Rhinogram

- Work with company stakeholders to iterate over new and existing features by using Sketch and Invision to design and manage complex and detailed prototypes.
- Actively develop and architect full feature sets for our web and mobile applications to deliver new and innovative additions to our platform.
- Bring UI/UX consistency across all of our platforms by creating standalone, maintainable components and managing Rhinostyle, our open sourced component library.
- Reduce end to end development time by introducing and leading bi-weekly frontend architecture meetings with the product and engineering teams.

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

10.2018 - 07.2020 | Rhinogram

- Spearheaded the implementation of a real-time WebRTC video chat feature, with cross browser consistency over mobile and desktop browsers.
- Created an intricate roles and permissions feature, allowing for highly granular rules permitting access to certain segments of the application.
- Developed seamless user experiences for our web and mobile applications using React,
   React Native and NodeJS.

# **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

11.2016 - 10.2018 | Launchpeer

- Took client ideas from concept to launch by building mobile and web applications across a
  wide range of sectors and scales.
- Wrote clean, reusable and maintainable code based on industry best practices.
- Communicated directly with clients, providing them with regular updates about the progress and development of their projects.

## **WEB DEVELOPER**

09.2016 - 02.2017 | Benefitfocus

- Designed, developed and implemented features and solutions for Benefitfocus' primary public facing website, benefitfocus.com.
- Deployed weekly builds and tested new features across different browsers.
- Built pixel perfect HTML email templates from PSD mockups.